SUKHDARSHAN VINAYAK Electronics Engineer

MOBILE EMAIL: GitHub LINKEDIN

9079977037 parasvinayak045@gmail.com <u>sukhdarshanvinayak</u> <u>sukhdarshanvinayak</u>

Summary

Highly motivated Electronics Engineer with 2 years of experience in embedded systems design and development. Demonstrates proficiency in schematic and PCB layout, test firmware development, and project team management. Seeking admission to a Master's program in Electronics and Electrical Engineering to deepen expertise and contribute to advancements in the field.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Electronics Engineer at Alfa Intellitech

(May 2022 - Current)

FPS Connect

- Schematic Capture, PCB design, Test Case creation, Debugging, and Test Firmware development.
- Used SIM module, ESP32, serial-to-serial convertor, and LDO for better power delivery.
- Communication protocols used AT Commands, SPI, and UART.
- Responsible for the quality of the product.

STAFFRON

- Schematic Capture, PCB design, Test Case creation, Debugging, and Test Firmware development.
- Integrated Camera, RFID, and LCD controlled through ESP32-S3.
- Used to manage attendance using face recognition and RFID authentication.
- Communication protocols used I2C, SPI, and UART.

BlackHawk

- Designed to manage the Forklift machine working.
- Managed a project team of six, focusing on debugging hardware and, firmware, and ensuring product quality.
- Had to check business logic through manual and unit testing.
- Equipped with STM32, ESP32, and 9-Axis Gyroscope
- Communication protocols include RS485, SPI, and UART.

Automatic Aquarium Care Taker:

- It was my first project, and we were a team of two
- Responsible for developing the Prototype and Final version.
- Including Schematic, PCB, Test Case, Debugging, and test firmware.
- Learned basics of C and C++ for embedded development.
- Microcontroller Used ESP32-S3, with 8 outputs including a motor controller, a Temperature Sensor, and a Camera.
- The communication protocol used UART for debugging the hardware and programming the microcontroller.

Front End Developer Intern at Newton School

(Aug 2021 - Feb 2022)

Facebook Login Page Clone:

- ❖ Learn HTML and CSS.
- Cloned Facebook login page using HTML and CSS.
- Published on GIT server.

Calculator:

- Learned basics of Javascript
- Built a web interface for the Calculator.
- Can do basic math operations like Addition, Subtraction, Multiplying, and dividing.
- Able to store the calculation history.

Age Calculator:

- Built a web interface for the Age Calculator
- Can calculate the user's age.

Cyber Security Intern at Cyberops Infosec LLP

(Jan 2021 - June 2021)

Responsibilities:

- Performing cyber and technical threat analyses.
- Discovering vulnerabilities in information systems.
- Analyzing Security System Logs, Security Tools, and Data.
- Generate VAPT report.

Personal PROJECTS

iLED Chaser:

- Developed IoT-based LED controller with motion sensors, utilizing ESP32 for control
- Developed a MOSFET driver to control different LED Strips using Shift Registers.
- Deployed on the local server for accessibility and utilized UART for communication.

iWiFi Switch:

- ❖ Designed IoT ON/OFF switch using ESP32.
- Efficiently work with 220-240v AC.
- Deployed on the local server for accessibility and utilized UART for communication

Training

Seldom India Technologies:

- Completed industrial training of 35 days on PLC, SCADA, and ACD.
- * Experience real-time monitoring in the industry using PLC and SCADA monitoring units.
- Learned the basics of PLC and SCADA and working principles.

Global Institute Of Technology:

- Completed industrial training of 15 days on Analysis Modeling, Simulation, and Image Processing.
- Organized by Global Institute Of Technology.
- Learned the basic use of MATLAB simulation and image processing.

Skills

- PCB Design
- Schematic Capture
- Layout Design
- Component Selection
- Gerber Generation
- SMT and Through hole Soldering
- Footprint Creation

- Kicad
- Altium Designer
- Embedded Systems Design
- Problem-Solving Skills
- Autodesk Fusion360
- Technical Documentation
- Project Management

INTERESTS

Bike Riding

Martial Arts

Gaming

Technology

EDUCATION

Global Institute Of Technology, Prince Uch Madhyamik **Blooming Dales** Skill India, Bachelors in Electronics & Vidyalaya, Sikar International Certified Communication Class XII - PCM School, Yoga Trainer Engineering (CBSE) Sri Ganganagar (BWS/Q2203) 2017 - 20212017 Class X (CBSE) 2021

CGPA: 6.75 CGPA: 5.47 2015 Percentage: 78%

CGPA: 8.00

Achievements

- 2 Gold Medals at the international level in Karate for India.
- Won Second prize in Intercollege Tech Fest.
- Participated in ROBOTICS workshop and made Line Follower car.
- Participated in the regional-level Quiz competition.
- Won 1st prize in the Kabaddi team game.
- Won 2nd prize in the 20KM Cycling Race.
- Volunteered in Pradhanmantri Swachhta Abhiyan and led a team of 4.
- Worked as Head of Discipline at college tech-fest.